{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "English_1",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "having a very pleasant taste or smell",
      "options": ["delicous", "delicious", "deliciuos", "delisious"],
      "answer": "delicious"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_2",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "a person in authority, especially over a body of troops or a military operation",
      "options": ["commmander", "comander", "commander", "commader"],
      "answer": "commander"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_3",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "to move rapidly downward through the air",
      "options": ["swoope", "swoop", "swop", "swoopt"],
      "answer": "swoop"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_4",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "resting in a high place",
      "options": ["perchd", "perched", "percheed", "percht"],
      "answer": "perched"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_5",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "a situation involving exposure to danger",
      "options": ["risck", "risk", "risq", "risc"],
      "answer": "risk"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_6",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "make (someone) feel annoyed or dissatisfied",
      "options": ["displese", "displease", "displeas", "displeese"],
      "answer": "displease"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_7",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "a gesture of respect or polite recognition, especially one made to or by a person when arriving or departing",
      "options": ["salute", "salut", "salue", "saloot"],
      "answer": "salute"
    },{
  "id": "English_8",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for soldiers.",
  "options": ["Team", "Army", "Fleet", "Class"],
  "answer": "Army"
},
{
  "id": "English_9",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for players.",
  "options": ["School", "Fleet", "Team", "Bunch"],
  "answer": "Team"
},
{
  "id": "English_10",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for students.",
  "options": ["Class", "Bunch", "Fleet", "Army"],
  "answer": "Class"
},
{
  "id": "English_11",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for grapes.",
  "options": ["Class", "Bunch", "School", "Team"],
  "answer": "Bunch"
},
{
  "id": "English_12",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for fish.",
  "options": ["Fleet", "School", "Army", "Team"],
  "answer": "School"
},
{
  "id": "English_13",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
  "reference": "Collective nouns are nouns which refer to a group of people, animals, or things of the same type",
  "question": "Write the collective noun for ships.",
  "options": ["Class", "Army", "Fleet", "Bunch"],
  "answer": "Fleet"
},
    {
      "id": "English_14",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for buyer.",
      "options": ["manager", "seller", "worker", "owner"],
      "answer": "seller"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_15",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for husband.",
      "options": ["wife", "daughter", "mother", "sister"],
      "answer": "wife"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_16",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for parent.",
      "options": ["teacher", "child", "adult", "brother"],
      "answer": "child"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_17",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for teacher.",
      "options": ["parent", "worker", "child", "student"],
      "answer": "student"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_18",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for brother.",
      "options": ["father", "sister", "teacher", "aunt"],
      "answer": "sister"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_19",
      "chapter": "A Faithful Act",
      "question": "Generate the binomial pair for doctor.",
      "options": ["nurse", "surgeon", "patient", "teacher"],
      "answer": "patient"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_20",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nGopal eats two bananas every day.",
      "options": ["eats", "Gopal", "bananas", "every day"],
      "answer": "Gopal"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_21",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nTom ran after Jerry.",
      "options": ["ran", "Tom", "Jerry", "after"],
      "answer": "Tom"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_22",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nMama Bear brought honey for Baby Bear.",
      "options": ["Mama Bear", "brought", "honey", "Baby Bear"],
      "answer": "Mama Bear"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_23",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nAlice went to Wonderland.",
      "options": ["went", "Alice", "Wonderland", "to"],
      "answer": "Alice"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_24",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nAnts collect food for winter.",
      "options": ["collect", "Ants", "food", "for winter"],
      "answer": "Ants"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_25",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nWe like to read books.",
      "options": ["We", "like", "read", "books"],
      "answer": "We"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_26",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nI can make tea.",
      "options": ["tea", "make", "I", "can"],
      "answer": "I"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_27",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nPinku broke my doll yesterday.",
      "options": ["broke", "my doll", "Pinku", "yesterday"],
      "answer": "Pinku"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_28",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nHarry Potter defeated the evil wizard.",
      "options": ["the", "Harry Potter", "defeated", "evil wizard"],
      "answer": "Harry Potter"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_29",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The subject in the following sentence is:\n\nA dragon was guarding the treasure.",
      "options": ["guarding", "was", "dragon", "treasure"],
      "answer": "dragon"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_30",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nGopal eats two bananas every day.",
      "options": ["Gopal", "eats two bananas every day", "bananas", "two"],
      "answer": "eats two bananas every day"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_31",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nTom ran after Jerry.",
      "options": ["Tom", "ran after Jerry", "Jerry", "after"],
      "answer": "ran after Jerry"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_32",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nMama Bear brought honey for Baby Bear.",
      "options": ["Mama Bear", "brought honey for Baby Bear", "honey", "Baby Bear"],
      "answer": "brought honey for Baby Bear"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_33",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nAlice went to Wonderland.",
      "options": ["Alice", "went to Wonderland", "Wonderland", "to"],
      "answer": "went to Wonderland"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_34",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nAnts collect food for winter.",
      "options": ["Ants", "collect food for winter", "food", "for winter"],
      "answer": "collect food for winter"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_35",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nWe like to read books.",
      "options": ["We", "like to read books", "books", "read"],
      "answer": "like to read books"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_36",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nI can make tea.",
      "options": ["I", "can make tea", "tea", "make"],
      "answer": "can make tea"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_37",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nPinku broke my doll yesterday.",
      "options": ["Pinku", "broke my doll yesterday", "my doll", "yesterday"],
      "answer": "broke my doll yesterday"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_38",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nHarry Potter defeated the evil wizard.",
      "options": ["Harry Potter", "defeated the evil wizard", "evil wizard", "defeated"],
      "answer": "defeated the evil wizard"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_39",
      "chapter": "The Subject and the Predicate",
      "question": "The predicate in the following sentence is:\n\nA dragon was guarding the treasure.",
      "options": ["A dragon", "was guarding the treasure", "guarding", "treasure"],
      "answer": "was guarding the treasure"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_40",
      "chapter": "Grammar Preliminaries",
      "question": "____________ will watch a film.",
      "options": ["us", "ourselves", "we", "ours"],
      "answer": "we"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_41",
      "chapter": "Grammar Preliminaries",
      "question": "_______________ have a pet dog.",
      "options": ["he", "she", "us", "I"],
      "answer": "I"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_42",
      "chapter": "Grammar Preliminaries",
      "question": "________________ are coming to our house on Sunday.",
      "options": ["us", "they", "them", "it"],
      "answer": "they"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_43",
      "chapter": "Grammar Preliminaries",
      "question": "Whose pencil is this? I found ___________ on the floor.",
      "options": ["he", "she", "them", "it"],
      "answer": "it"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_44",
      "chapter": "Grammar Preliminaries",
      "question": "Do ___________ like dancing?",
      "options": ["you", "he", "them", "us"],
      "answer": "you"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_45",
      "chapter": "The Sentence",
      "question": "Rearrange the following words to form a meaningful sentence:\n\ntoys of full The is bag",
      "options": ["is full bag toys of The", "The bag is full of toys", "toys bag full The is of", "full is The toys bag of"],
      "answer": "The bag is full of toys"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_46",
      "chapter": "Questions",
      "question": "Rearrange the following words to form a meaningful question:\n\nbook Henu is a reading?",
      "options": ["Henu is reading a book?", "Is reading Henu a book?", "book Henu is reading a?", "Is Henu reading a book?"],
      "answer": "Is Henu reading a book?"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_47",
      "chapter": "Questions",
      "question": "Rearrange the following words to form a meaningful question:\n\nthe ships harbour in are the?",
      "options": ["The ships are in the harbour?", "Are in the harbour ships the?", "Are the ships in the harbour?", "Harbour the are ships in?"],
      "answer": "Are the ships in the harbour?"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_48",
      "chapter": "Questions",
      "question": "Rearrange the following words to form a meaningful question:\n\nfor they party a going are?",
      "options": ["Are they going for a party?", "They are going for a party?", "For a party they going are?", "Going they for a party are?"],
      "answer": "Are they going for a party?"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_49",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["bag", "bed", "biscuit", "Maya"],
      "answer": "Maya"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_50",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["cup", "plate", "China", "spoon"],
      "answer": "China"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_51",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["bread", "butter", "cheese", "Amul"],
      "answer": "Amul"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_52",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["break", "chocolate", "cake", "Safal"],
      "answer": "Safal"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_53",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["boy", "Mumbai", "girl", "man"],
      "answer": "Mumbai"
    },
    {
      "id": "English_54",
      "chapter": "Nouns: Common, Proper, Collective",
      "topic": "Common Nouns",
      "question": "Identify the word that is NOT a common noun.",
      "options": ["dog", "mouse", "Tommy", "cat"],
      "answer": "Tommy"
    }
  ]
}

